hello welcome back so few housekeeping
things the circling Institute is now
doing all of their offerings online so
if you've been interested in partaking
in circling there won't be the distance
barrier anymore and and that's been
working out really really well I had my
doubts however I found it to be pretty
profoundly effective and even more
effective than in some cases in doing
circling so I'm pretty excited about
this and so I hope to see some of you
and and all the information is below the
circling Institute website and also the
Facebook pages where you can see all of
our events if you want to do one-on-one
work with me my emails below just go
ahead and email me let me know and
[Music]
I think that's it so this is I believe
episode 5 of this series of Chris and I
reading the Platonic dialogues and I was
I played Socrates this one and you can I
just want to say in advance you get to
watch guy struggle through all of the
Greek names of people I think I'm gonna
be speaking with a limp for the next
week after that whole experience but we
did a lot of reading in the front end of
it and we started to really dial like
dialogue about it I think somewhere
around midway through so uh there's also
a link below to the to the translation
that we're reading from and you can
download that from scribe for free and
I'll put the page number that we started
that so you can I definitely would
recommend reading along if you can and
I'm excited I missed I'm really glad
that I'm doing this with Chris he's so
is such a beautiful being and the way
that he so naturally
weaves cosmics with his language is
learning a lot through this and just
really appreciative appreciate our flow
and also watching how many different
dimensions of intelligibility the
Socratic dialogues
our and I just we just started the first
one we're not even probably halfway
through it and I'm just like whoa so
much here so it's a journey thanks for
joining us much love
now all right so why don't you start
with that line then and take it away
whenever you like okay so we're on this
is this is a page 574 if you're just if
you're new to this just there's a out
put a link down to where you can get the
copy that we're reading from I'm PDF for
free and I'll be Socrates and actually
you know somebody's you got it all right
so you don't waver about what you don't
know if in fact you know that you don't
know apparently not
don't you realize that the air in our
conduct are caused by the kind of
ignorance of thinking that we know when
we don't know what do you mean by that
well we don't set set out to do
something unless we think we know what
we're doing right right but when people
don't think they know how to do
something they hand it over to somebody
else
right of course so the sort of people
who don't think who don't think they
know how to do things
makes no difference in life because they
leave those things to other people
you're right well who are the ones
making this mistake surely not the ones
who know of course not well since it's
not those who know and it's not those
who don't know and no they don't know is
there anyone left exist except those who
don't know but stink they they do no no
they're the only ones left so this is
the ignorance that causes bad things
this is the most disgraceful sort of
stupidity yes and isn't it most harmful
and most
contemptible when it is ignorance of the
most important things very much so
well can you name anything more
important than what's just and in my
herbal and good and advantageous no I
really can't but aren't those the things
you say you're wavering about yes so if
you're if you're wavering it's obvious
from what we've said that not only are
you ignorant about the most important
things but you also think you know what
you don't know I guess that's right
good God
alka bodies what sort of state you're in
I hesitate to call it by name but still
since we're alone it must be said you
are wedded to stupidity my good fellow
stupidity is the highest degree of our
discussions and your own words convinced
you of it this is why you're rushing
into politics before you've got an
education you're not alone um you're not
alone okay
weird you're not alone in this state the
sad state you've got most of our cities
politicians for company there are there
are only a few exceptions among them
perhaps your guardian persons yes
Socrates and people do say that he
didn't acquire his expertise all by
himself he kept company with many
experts like the fuck ladies and annex a
giris even now despite his advanced age
he consults with Damon for the same
purpose really have you ever seen any
expert who is unable to make others
expert in what he knows the person who
taught you how to read and write he
had expertise in his field and he made
you and anybody else he like expert as
well didn't he yes
and will you having learned from him be
able to teach somebody yes and isn't it
the same with the music teacher and the
gym the gymnastics teacher certainly I
think we can be pretty sure that someone
understands something when he can can
show that he has made someone else
understand it we were just talking about
this weren't we before we started
recording yeah you and I right yeah
thought that right the relationship
between the teacher and their on
pedagogy Ram that's a nice that's a nice
little coincidence there yeah I'm sorry
um I'll try not to do that I what did I
just sir I agree I agree well then can
you tell me who personal is that how
he's been pronounced I think it's
apparent Eric Lee Pericles Pericles okay
well then can you tell me who Pericles
has made into an expert shall we start
with his son but Socrates both of his
sons turned out to be idiots
what about and how do you say that one
cliff it gets clean yes cleanness what
about cleanse your brother there's no
point talking about him he's a madman
well then since clitoris is a madman and
Perkis sons were idiots why shall we say
in the reason that he allowed you to be
in the state you're in
I suppose it's because I didn't really
pay attention but can you name any other
Athenian or foreigner slave or free who
became any more of an expert by keeping
company with pickles after all
name pythor Dias son of Aeschylus how do
you say that once and I think III
Psilakis I salikus and and Cialis son of
colitis who became wise through their
association with Xena they paid him a
hundred a hundred minds each and became
famous experts I can't think of anyone
by Zeus
very well what do you propose for
yourself do you intend to remain in your
present condition or practice some self
cultivation let's discuss it together
Socrates you know I do see what you're
saying and I actually agree actually I
agree it seems to me that none of our
city's politicians has been properly
educated except for a few and what does
that mean well if they were educated
than anyone who wanted to compete with
them would have had to get some
knowledge and go into training like an
athlete but as it is since they entered
politics as amateurs there's no need for
me to train and go to the trouble of
learning I'm sure my natural abilities
will be far superior to theirs
good god my dear boy what a thing to say
how unworthy of your good looks and your
other advantages what in the world do
you mean Socrates what are you getting
at I'm furious with you and my
infatuation for you
why because you stoop to compete with
these people who else have I got to
compete with that's a fine sort of
question from a man who thinks he holds
himself in high esteem
what do you mean aren't they my
competitors look here if you were
intending to steer a steer a ship into
battle we would you be content to be the
best sailor at steering granted that
necessary but wouldn't you keep your eye
on the real opponents and not on your
comrades as you're as you're doing now
surely you ought to be so far superior
to them that they're happy to be your
humble comrades in the struggle and
wouldn't dream of competing with you I'm
assuming that you do really intend to
distinguish yourself with some splendid
deed worthy of you and your city yes
that's certainly what I intend to do
dear me how very poor it is for you to
be satisfied with being better than the
soldiers how proper not to keep an eye
on the leaders of the opposing camp so
that you can some day become better than
them by training and scheming against
them who are you talking about Socrates
don't you know that our city is at war
from time to time with the Spartans and
the end the great king of Persia you're
right so since you plan to be leader of
the city and wouldn't it be wouldn't it
be right to think that your struggle is
with the king of Sparta or Persia that
may well be true okay so so like so
right now he's he's it sounds to me he's
revealing he's revealing his folly
big time I mean he's been just kind of
deconstructing him through this whole
thing
[Laughter]
now he's revealing that he doesn't know
where to aim for the enemy like or who
the enemy is so this is where it starts
to get into this wisdom because the
question of wisdom it seems yeah and the
right level of resolution to direct his
sense of organization as well right like
when he says you know you were intending
to steer a ship into battle would you be
content to be the best sailor at
steering right right right and and right
would you would you would you interpose
yourself into the role of the one sailor
steer right or would you
or now maybe I'm interpolating this but
but it can't help but remind me a little
bit of the Phaedrus the chariot myth of
the Phaedrus right that it involves a
greater sense of coherence and
organization that directs and Orient's
attention where it ought to be right
it's not just the one role the one
position have to pick the right level of
resolution for the organization right
it's not just the one horse it's the
coherent view of the horses right it's
not just the one sailor
it's the co-operative organization of
the sailors yeah that aims attention to
the right opponent right you're right
you're know who your comrades are and
know who your enemy is right died right
and your attention in such a way that
you can gather yourself around the
optimal organization that you need in
order to be rational right because
that's what the right that's what that's
what the sense of rationality is right
it's the co hearing at the right level
of resolution look at the right things
pay attention to the right things right
and so the Alka by T's is he's not only
not paying attention to the right things
but he doesn't know that he's not even
looking to pay attention to the right
thing that he's not even not looking
right so something else is going on so
he's it seems like he's Socrates cos
keeps on unpinning every pin of
certainty he has about knowing including
cruise talking in the conversation right
great right right right right right and
and it's it I have the same clothing
that he's trying to he's trying to evoke
his appetite for opponent his his his
opponent appetites but to redirect his
opponent appetites into the right
opponent process he knows that term
right yeah yeah I'll take great but what
is it am i but what sort of notion is
that is that the right place
ah see did you do that that larger chunk
from Socrates already after that all
that may all will be true
[Music]
but I startup up with okay yeah okay let
me just do that part we'll start a
little store from there no sir you've
got to keep an eye on middle as Midea
s-- the cockfighter and such people
people try to run the city's affairs
with their slave boy hairstyles as the
women say still she still showing on
their boorish minds i think that's my
new favorite line they fit out to
flatter the city with their outlandish
talk not to rule it these are the people
I'm telling you you've got to keep your
eyes on so relax don't bother to learn
what needs to be learned for the great
struggle to come don't train yourself
for what needs training go ahead and go
into politics with your with with your
complete and thorough preparation know
Socrates I think you're right but I
still don't think the Spartan generals
or the Persian King are any different
from anyone else but what sort of notion
is that think about it about what in the
first place when when do you think you'd
cultivate yourself if you feared them
and thought they were form it for mid
formed a bubble form the bull or if you
didn't obviously if I thought they were
formidable surely you don't think that
cultivating yourself will do any harm do
you not at all in fact it would be a big
help so that's one flaw in this notion
of yours a big flaw isn't it you're
right now the second flaw is that it's
also false judging by the probabilities
what do you mean is it like the natural
talents will be great among noble
families or another fan
in noble families obviously those are
well born those who those who are well
born will turn out to be perfectly
virtuous if they're well brought up
won't they they certainly will so let's
compare our situation with theirs and
consider first of all whether the
Spartan and Persian kings are a humbler
descent we know of course that the
Spartan Kings are descended from
Hercules and the Persian kings are
descended from King Akiba knees and that
the families of Hercules and Achilles go
right back to Persia son of Zeus mine to
Socrates my family goes back to let's
give this a try your cities your ass and
cheese let's go with that and your wrist
cheese goes back to Zeus so it does mine
too so so does mine too
Alka biteys mine goes back to Dan these
Greek words it makes me do stuff with my
tongue that I can't I'd say I'd say take
your time I have a tendency to want to
rush through them and that's I think the
wrong instincts or really take your time
you've got it you got it so so there's
mine too Noble Alka biteys mine goes
back to Daedalus and Daedalus goes back
to a fetus son of Zeus Hephaestus I
think Estes son of Zeus starting with
those kings though and tracing backwards
every one of them is a king all the way
back to Zeus kings of argos and sparta
and kings of persia and in eternity and
sometimes of Asia too as they are now
but you and I are private citizens
were our fathers and if you had to show
off your ancestors of and Salamis the
native land of year see your sekiz your
your sickies to our tent okay
I think it's honored as art I think it's
artaxerxes artaxerxes son of their
circuses Xerxes or Agee Aegina the
native land of um Akos the ancestors I
haven't liked wrestling in my mouth from
those many times sister said your saw
your sauces don't you realize your
sauces how do you say that one and
sisters of your uri sauce I think I said
I think it was it's either yarissa
cheese or yarissa keys you're you're a
circus you're a circus Arisa your wrist
case it's a multiple choice yes me about
whichever one I could say that's the one
it is you're a circus
well my phonetic phonetic ancient Greece
needs some need some work maybe we'll
devote one of these one of these videos
to just ancient Greek ancient Greek
phonetics yeah absolutely
I like yes I'll speak with a limb for
about a week after in jokes like that do
you realize how much you you'd be
laughed at but you think were the equal
of those men in the dignity of our
descent as well as in our upbringing
haven't you noticed what
commanding position the Spartan Kings
enjoy their wives are guarded at public
expense by the the ephors
so as to ensure as far as possible that
their Kings are descended from the
family of herakleides alone and as the
Persian King his position is so supreme
that no nobody so much as suspects is
here of being fathered by anybody but
him
that's why his queen is left unguarded
except by fear what the eldest son and
here the to the throne is bull is born
all Kings subject have a feast day then
in the years that follow the whole of
Asia celebrates that day the King's
birthday with further sacrifice and
feast but when we are born Alka biteys
even the neighbors hardly notice it as
the cosmic poet says then then the boy
is brought up did you want to say
something there no no I'm just saying
just yeah good then the boys brought up
not by some nanny of no account but by
the most highly respected okay you know
eunuchs in the royal household
what's he eunuchs do you know well I
don't know if I don't know if that means
a eunuch in the in the in the typical
and perhaps pejorative sense of the term
yeah let's let's come back to that I'm
here I'm not sure if I'm not sure if
they mean the eunuch in the sense that
we know the term to be right well circle
back except he sounds like a like a
nanny or something maybe but behind the
most highly respect to eunuchs no maybe
not yeah in the royal household they
attend to all the needs of the infant
child and are especially concerned to
make him as handsome as possible shaping
and straightening his infant limbs
and for this they are held up in great
esteem when the boys reached 7 years of
age they take up horseback riding in
with the instructors and begin to hunt
wild game when he is twice 7 years
the boy is entrusted to people called
the Royal tutors these are for Persians
of mature age who have been selected as
the best the wisest the justice and most
self-controlled and the bravest the
first of them instructs him in the
worship of their gods the the may be and
lore of Zeus
Zoroaster son of horror Roman Maz says
hora Mazdas and also in what the King
should know the justice man teaches him
to be truthful his whole life long the
most self-controlled man teaches him not
to be the mastered by by even thus a
single pleasure so that he can get
accustomed to being a free man and a
real king whose first duty is to rule
himself not to be a slave of himself the
bravest man trains him to be fearless
and undaunted because fears slavery
that's intense but but for you alka
bodies / circles
chose from among his household
zou frías
if three threatens Thracian Thracian a
tutor so old it was perfectly useless I
could tell you about all the rest of the
upbringing and education of your
competitors but it would be a long story
and besides you could probably imagine
the later stages from what I've told you
so far but Alka by tease your
your upbringing and your education or
that of any other Athena is of no
concern to anybody to tell the truth
nobody that is except perhaps some man
who may happen to be in love with you
again if you care to consider the wealth
of the Persians the splendor the clothes
and the trade trailing robes the
anointings
with ma Mira the throng of servants in
waiting in all their other luxuries
you'd be ashamed of your circumstances
because you'd see how inferior they are
to theirs again if you care to consider
the self-control and the decorum of the
Spartans their confidence and their
composure their self-esteem and their
discipline their courage and their
fortitude and their love of hardship
victory and honor you'd consider
yourself a mere child in all these
respects again we'd better discuss your
wealth
alka buddies if you're to see where you
stand you may devote yourself to it and
think it makes you something but if you
care to look at the wealth of the
spartans you'd realize that it greatly
exceeds ours in Athens they have land of
their own and in the mezzanine that not
a single one of our states could compete
with not in size nor wallet II nor in
slaves especially helots nor even in
horses nor in other livestock grazing
and missing but I'll pass over all that
you should try to read it Socrates you
try to pass over that there there is
more gold and silver and Sparta in price
hands than the rest of Greece put
together it's been coming into them for
many generations pouring in from all of
Greece's cities and offering from
foreign cities too and it never goes out
again it's just like what the Fox say to
the lion in a Sophie's Fayette fable you
can clearly see the tracks of the money
going in toward Sparta but the tracks
coming out are nowhere to be seen you
can be sure that the Spartans are the
richest of the Greeks in gold and silver
and that the king is the richest of all
the Spartans because the greatest share
of these revenues go goes to him
furthermore he receives a considerable
sum the Spartans by way of royal tribute
but great as they are when compared to
other Greek cities the Spartans fortunes
are nothing comparable with the fortunes
of the Persians and their King I once
spoke with a reliable man who traveled
over to the Persian court and he told me
that he crossed a very large and rich
tract of land nearly a day's journey
across which the locals call the queen
of girdle there's there's another one
called the Queen's Vale as well as many
others all fine and rich properties each
one named for a part of the Queen's
wardrobe because each one is set aside
to pay for the Queen's finery
now suppose someone were to say to a
[Music]
mistress the king's mother and the widow
of zeros quote the son of demonic and
dimanche intent instead to challenge
your son the Wardrobe is worth only 50 -
at best and her son has less than 300
acres of land at orchha
think she'd be wondering what this Alka
biteys had up his sleeve to think of
competing against arced our Texas's I
think she'd say I don't see what his
fellow could be relying on except
diligence and wisdom the Greeks don't
have anything else worth mentioning but
if she heard that this alkyl biteys who
is making his attempt isn't in the first
place
hardly twenty years old and and secondly
entirely uneducated and furthermore when
his lover tells him to study and
cultivate himself and discipline himself
so that he can compete with the King he
says he doesn't want to and that he's
happy with the way he is if she heard
all that I think she'd ask in amazement
what in the world could this youngster
be relying on suppose we we were to
reply good looks height birth wealth and
native intelligence then Alka biteys
considering all that they have of these
things as well she'd conclude that we
were stark raving mad again I think that
lamp IDO the daughter of leoch ladies
life of our kite amis kharkom arkad amis
and mother of Aegeus who were all
Spartan Kings would be similarly amazed
if you with your bad upbringing proposed
to compete with her son
considering all his advantages and yet
don't you think it's disgraceful that
even our enemies wives have a better
appreciation than we do of what it would
take to challenge them no my excellent
friend trust in me and in the Delphic
inscription and quote know thyself
unquote
these are the people we must defeat not
the ones you think and we have no hope
of defeating them unless we act with
both diligence and skill if you fall
shorten these then you will fall short
of achieving Fame in Greece as well as
abroad and that is what I think you're
longing for more than anyone else ever
longed for anything
I'm gonna go guy go ahead take a sip of
water no doubt so what are you getting
so far with this it's like though it's
like the the longest it's a pretty
elaborate wake-up call yeah but a wake
up call it is a wake up call it is you
know right and I mean there's a lot in
there
but among them is the you know the the
the proffered revelation that if you're
going to if you're going to rest upon
these laurels if you're going to seek
refuge and all that you have you may as
well draw your sword
they draw your self in comparison to the
highest order of magnitude that exists
within that mode right yeah yeah to its
greatest scale yeah and I mean it's a
it's a it's it's a it's it's humiliating
and the proper sense of the term
humiliate yeah yeah totally
right if this is your ambition then your
ambition must be humiliated by you by us
exploring the ultimate in which that
particular mode of appetite would be
relevant yeah yeah and once we elevate
it to that scale the motive appetite all
of a sudden becomes revealed for its
proper nature mmm-hmm right and it's
it's so it's so interesting to be alka
by Dee's listening to this imagine yeah
right East it's for him to attend in
that way or
see in that way he must be someone
different than who he is yeah yeah he's
riding the view from above right as it
has it zoom is higher and higher as he's
retreated he's he's meant to he's born
away from himself further and further
and further away with this continental
view yeah of this like that his
provisions are yes he's revealed
he's been revealed as he's been revealed
in his scarcity mm-hmm yeah true true
scarcity right his abundance his
relative abundance has revealed to be to
be tremendously scarce and and if that
becomes you your way of grounding
out your identity and it's revealed to
be so scarce than what do you have left
this has been dispossessed of the very
things that constitute you and your
knowing and your excellence
what excellence is what excellence have
you left to wield if if it was if it was
predicated on something that was so so
good till very contingent it's very
contingent on a level of resolution that
Socrates is just deprived him of right
right yeah let's compare you now to the
Spartans let's compare you now to the
Persian right thank you you're really
you're you're you're you're a whole lot
of nothing my friend
so it's interesting because it's like
it's I think if you look at this as the
if we zoom out and look at what's
happening in the dialogue right and what
is the dialogue doing it's like it's
it's shifting and it's doing something
right so there's like what Socrates is
literally saying right and what Alka by
Jesus is saying and back and forth but
what is that showing us right hmm and I
and I think it's like somehow Socrates
is the finger that's pointing to it's
not just that he hasn't he hasn't
understood those things it's it's it's
he's somehow getting him to see yeah
from a different from a different
vantage from so he's taking him
somewhere right he has he's understood
them but he hasn't Dupree
yeah yeah and no so so like so how is he
so how is how is appreciation starting
to dawn on him like what is Socrates
doing so it's like one thing he's
zooming out right it's a peripatetic
right he's dog Socrates is actually
taking him like Socrates could have he's
very easily said to him you know listen
you're your comparative abundance your
comparative wealth your comparative
handsomeness is really quite miniscule
if we were a parrot to those who have it
in such greater quantity and such we
have a volume he could have just said
that I mean there's more than that going
on in this in this monologue but he
could have said that in a much busier
way but instead what he did is he he
very very slowly very gradually and in a
graduating fashion do amanhã
took him on a journey that's it and he
he made him he made him live his
scarcity right he made him live it and
he made us live it right that was a
difference and that's the difference
between that's the difference between
the understanding in the in the shallow
sense of the term
and the appreciation and yeah right
is that is that the appreciation is is
lived yes Socrates forces him to live it
and of course exactly so of course you
I'm for it unfortunate for guys in stock
to live it yeah well it's also that just
didn't die in dialogue big this is
what's possible right that this is like
we're you know and kind of bringing back
in this thing that John's been really
you know and I've been realizing along
with him about you know in the psycho
technologies in our practices we've that
it may may it may be necessary right for
us to engage in philosophy ax right and
in in sacred dialogue that is not like
something that it'd be nice if it was
there right it may it may be something
that's that it that that is necessary
like the that our practices
that engaging in this kind of dialogue
that make these kinds of shifts in one's
identity in perspective is something
that's actually necessary and not
optional for us so I'm just kind of
thinking about that just kind of
bringing that along bringing myself
along as we're as we were reading this
because I also know that um gonzales
talks about this of where you know
there's all these Jews we talked before
there's all these different ways to read
Plato right there's been just
historically all these different fights
and viewpoints about like you know what
was Plato trying to do was he trying to
do anything is there a system underneath
it is it just art you know there's all
these different views I mean in Gonzales
was kind of pointing in a honing in on
that the first number of dialogues were
[Music]
were were we're basically trying to like
Plato trying to see if he could get wake
people up to the philosophical life
right like how do you get from how do
you get somebody who doesn't see and
they don't see that they don't see to
see right um that that to do what it
took to live with philosophic life could
be because they could actually see it
first of all to then be attracted to it
or choose it or not right and so that
there's a visit there's a strange thing
that goes on there because what it takes
on some level is in order to see it you
must that presupposes the transformation
that it takes to see it right because if
you see if this is the if this is the
philosophical life we'll say right this
is the the the the outcome of the
transformation from down here what I see
will well I won't be able to actually
see what's there I will have to be
somebody that could see it right so she
said the first number of dot dialogues
on the earliest dialogues were this
these kind of these battles back and
forth of like these dead ends and and
and people for the longest time
interpreted that is Plato
working out I think working out his
system right through Socrates or
something like that but actually the
Gazala says no he's in a certain sense
he's showing that not not everyone's
gonna be able to wake up to it right and
that he's taking you through these right
these dead ends and all this kind of
stuff today I think showing and so the
part of my listening is kind of their
look like well okay so is alkyl alkyl
bodies is he getting it right and like
what does it take to get it so one of
the things in the beginning is we talked
about you know how did Socrates get him
to play along right well by actually
playing along then set it up right yes
and by Bute bent by beautifying him
before his eyes right we were talking
about that before about there's a
certain that buttering that he does just
enough to appeal to his sense of
self-importance and enough to seduce him
into the process that's ultimately going
to problem of the self-importance if he
can become the kind of person who can
appreciate being robbed of his
self-importance right so right now
there's a strain a can he become the
kind of person that can appreciate the
very thing that he's coming to know and
if he can't then he can't ultimately
come to know it but then there's that
tension that tension which ultimately
has a threshold in most of these
dialogues and we're going to come to it
or not but that he must become the kind
of person that can appreciate the can
appreciate the insight that is emerging
through this dialogue the very insight
that the dialogue is actually trying to
surface or the very appreciation that
the dialogue is trying to surface hmm
yeah right so he has to find he has to
conform himself into the patterning of
the dialogue in order to actually
understand where it's meant to lead him
yes so yeah you can see I'm glad you
said that the tension because I can feel
the binding I can feel it in myself as
trying to work it out there is this kind
of tension
going on and there is the sense with
Willie get it is he getting it is he
capable of getting it right will is ego
like basically that I I'm thinking a lot
about just you know how do you deal with
somebody with like a really gripped
immature ego right right right
so interesting yeah all right so should
I read that last part over again oh I'm
just kidding
oh yeah first occupiers worry I'll ad
one one stop yeah yeah well Socrates
what kind of self-cultivation do I need
to practice can you show me the way
but you said really sounded true kiss
her right there so he's asked she so
it's interesting that's a different that
seems different well originally yeah
what kind of self communities within
bamboozled totally well he sees it
enough to have it be attractive enough
to ask him a question about it and who
knows if it's willing it's it's either
attractive enough for its but musing
enough right yeah that's the thing I
mean you know we're I think we've
probably both had the feeling of being
of being in dialog where someone has has
spotted is posited something that is so
if so complex are incomprehensible or
something to which we have no no obvious
response yeah right like when you push
someone to the point where there's their
their ability to respond coherently
because maybe you've overwhelmed the
overwhelmed them with through it with
encyclopedia or because you've you've
somehow presented a complex argument
that has that that the person hasn't
fully absorbed yet
how does a person respond to being so
bamboozled in that way right that's it
that's a that's a decisive moment in any
given dialogue because all you can do at
that point I think if you're a genuine
interlocutor all you can do at that
point is to say well what you say sounds
true provisionally I don't know I don't
fully understand it yet say more right
because now all of a sudden you
created an object for my aspiration
you've created something that exceeds me
if I can speak in two volumes that
exceed me then there's something
seductive about that right if I have any
sense of ambition and the and the
attitude of that ambition can be
redirected to something that exceeds me
because Socrates has spent this whole
time showing elsif IDs that there's
actually a great deal that exceeds him
yeah right
right trying to draw out his appetite
and be directed to those things so as a
genuine interlocutor and it seems that
else of IDs is genuine right in his
willingness to play with Socrates he's
going to play genuinely he's going to
have to admit at this point that that he
has no there's no obvious response
there's no obvious way of reducing
everything that Socrates has said to any
one of his his his handy or available
propositions right so what do you say at
that point what do you say you say well
I'm stumped and I'm discouraged and I'm
gonna leave this conversation and some
of Socrates interlocutors and his other
dialogues do just that right they go
okay peace out Socrates I'm done I'm
done for the day you know this is more
than I bargained for
or they're forced to say well I might
not I might not be in the position to
acquiesce to well you've said because
they might not understand all that
you've said but I'm I'm pretty
overwhelmed by it so the right thing to
do seems to be to cautiously
precariously just keep stumbling along
really and hope that you're going to
catch me at some point yeah absolutely
know that and that whole idea of
Socratic faith now is insinuating itself
in right huh huh kradic fate is that so
John John and John and Jordan were
talking about Socratic faith is the
continuity of contact mm-hmm the
continuity of contact right is that
Socratic faith or is that something else
I think it's related to Socratic faith I
don't know if I'm yeah I don't know if
that content I think the Socratic faith
that in the way that John has been
talking about is something like the the
notion of proleptic rationality right
right that the prolepsis of aspiration
that we've been dying with that we were
when we were back when we were reading
the paper a few a few of our sessions
ago right we were talking about that
right that Cowboys notion of proleptic
rationality as the orientation to the
the orientation to the epistemic had
that as yet unaccounted function is to
mediate the relationship between us and
what is what is epidemic ly unattainable
for us at any given time and so that
connection so the continuity of that
connection with the continuity that's
medias like the Socratic symbol on is
that relationship that is that is
continuous only because of the
intervention you have the Socratic
figure is that motton what what I'm
understanding to be this kind of
Socratic faith that John's talking about
right so interesting is it a commitment
the inter personal commitment to
Socrates yeah the inter personal
commitment to Socrates is the is the is
this
disposition of and is the social and
symbolic disposition of our commitment
to the process that Socrates affects
yeah right which is ultimately the
wisdom that comes from from graduating
perspective away from oneself as we give
ourselves over more and more to the
carriage of Socratic thinking yes
right as we surrender more into Socrates
we're surrendering right we're
surrendering ourselves not into a social
relationship though we are we're
surrendering ourselves back into the
ontological relationship right that's
why it's our duties rests at the point
where the to the vertical and the
horizontal axes meet yeah yeah it's it's
we know it's interesting is I'm I'm I'm
like feeling into this what we're
talking about right and then I'm like
okay yeah it's kind it's starting to
come into view but it's but but I'm also
really aware it's not in the view yet
it's calling to me like I'm sitting
there going like AB listening like all
that that's I'm some level I would
imagine that something like Socrates
guiding us right now
you know there's yes there's something
that that I'm starting to appreciate did
by aspiration to understand it right but
yet I don't have I don't fully have
understand what I'm trying to understand
but what I don't understand it's calling
to me that okay interesting
really Alcibiades would sympathize I
imagine yes I think us in a very similar
position absolutely that's great which
is why listening into Socrates
especially in that that big long section
that you just read bravely and listening
in to Socrates right we're listening in
with the year of our societies
ultimately
right yeah yeah yeah I've noticed that
yeah listen and feel ourselves being
unclasped by everything that Socrates is
just describing of him right yeah it's
interesting to see who Socrates is in
our listening all right in his listening
it's
as he's going along interested yeah yeah
um so I'm at top of 581 Socrates let's
see yes yes but let's discuss together
how we can become as good as possible
you know what I said about the need for
education applies to me as well as to
you we're in the same condition except
one respect what my guardian is better
and wiser than whistles your guardian
who's that Socrates God alka biteys it
was a God who prevented me from talking
with you before today I put my faith in
him and I say that your glory will be
entirely my doing you're teasing me
secretase maybe but I'm right in saying
that we stand in need of our
self-cultivation
actually every human being needs
self-cultivation but especially the two
of us so that detail at which Socrates
mentions at the very top of the dialogue
the detail that the same God that his
the diamond that entreats Socrates and
that Spurs Socrates to engage in seduce
also by these that same influence also
prevented him from doing so before this
exact juncture I think that's a very
very very important detail it's a very
important detail right because the
readiness of Alcibiades to be seduced
into the dialogic practice is the
emergence of that readiness is precisely
the affordance for his participation
right that there is a time in which
someone is actually ready to be thrust
into his own ignorance and to be it is
possessed of himself in the way that's
oh Jesus now yeah in the way that
Socrates is now dispossessing him and
there had to be a certain participant
willingness if right at least at least a
potential for it in order for this to be
a fruitful encounter in order for it to
be a fruitful undertaking right so that
well I think that's interesting because
you know we've talked before about how
that that the platonic seduction that's
on display here right that that Socrates
is using a variety of different
socialized means and devices to to
invite Alcibiades into the process that
will ultimately change him but that
there are certain conditions for that
practice that even Socrates had to have
had to wait for he had to have a certain
amount of forbearance and he restrained
himself yeah and I think that's that's
an interesting detail so then the
intuition the intuition of knowing how
and when to intervene the Kairos I guess
we could say the intuition for the
Kairos is something that was that
Socrates is saying was impressed was and
he was impressed by from without huh
right he had to know when yeah he
couldn't just intervene at any juncture
he had to know where to enter wind yeah
when to intervene yeah right I I think
that's that's a very important detail
not only for the die not only for the
sort of the dramaturgical stood you know
situation in the dialogue but also for
the Socratic sciences in general the
intervention has to be time the
intervention attended just so Kent right
yeah yeah I have to say I think that's I
would say well I mean in some level like
having having engaged in in a lot of
ways kradic inquiry for since that was
in my early 20s I would say that our in
the beginning it was so clumsy right
precise
because we would we wouldn't know when
to engage with what right Mike and I
would have to say that my that becoming
cultivated in the practice and growing
wiser and the practice and becoming
better at it has a lot to do with the
timing right just having your pulse on
like when to step in and when to say
something when to not say something when
to like let it all go haywire there's
there is a yeah it's interesting there
it's so it's so it's so interesting
because it just seems like the only
thing that could teach you that is the
is that is the process of doing it right
like you can't you can't give a series
of propositions or a set of steps and
say go through this because it seems to
be it's not a skill in that no it's it's
it's an intuition
it's a capacity right yeah it's like a
capacity to listen and to feel into it
alright and it is it does feel more like
a body thing it's like a place that you
sit and then look like you couldn't
explain it's hard to explain how you
knew that after the fact
do you definitely can't do it during the
case cuz that takes you right out of the
looking a little being into it's so
interesting that what you just said of
like where to enter me where did well I
guess that's I guess that's the case
with almost everything right cuz sure
we're always in a relationship we're
always in a we always have a life you
could right there's always something
that you can do to make something worse
now or at least not make it worse but
also don't make it better but that
knowing when to bring pressure in and
knowing what to pay attention to yeah
yeah but also right yeah what also it
also it's exactly right it also starts
to it it also implies that there is a
necessary synchronization with the world
well that has to happen in this process
right the system
you sort of undertake with some kind of
a Thomas autonomous agency yeah this is
a this is a cooperative this is a
cooperative synchronization with the
world right with a given s of the world
yeah that has to be done synchronously
with the opportunity that that you are
presented with right right you're you
have to work with you have to you have
to work with you have to work with your
given Asst to help - yes - but again
that plugs back into the the metaphor of
midwifery right because you you're
you're helping to deliver it but you
have to know just when just how you know
you're not as as the the Midwife is not
responsible for the pregnancy right the
midwife is responsible for assuring it
across the threshold properly um you
know so the readiness the nimbleness
right you know the the lifelessness you
have to have that the attention you have
to have all of those things but none of
them none of them imply that you're that
you're somehow producing this from
nothing
yes you think you're helping to Gaia
you're simply helping to guide it right
that the world the opportunity right the
has the opportunity has opened
irrespective of your attention to it but
it is precisely the combination of the
opportunity and your attention to it
it's precisely the convergence of your
attention to the world you know
potential implicit in the world yeah
total in the bond and the binding that
is affected by that relational yeah that
relational symbiosis that actually
intervenes in this process and helps to
into Midwife it helps to ring yeah
there's that Midway thing yeah there's
definitely that's the answer
it comes in right because Socrates
because Socrates says it's almost as
though again if we're sort of to extend
the metaphor little bit socrates has
been waiting cautiously in the wings
here in the margins of Alcibiades life
at least as he self-reports it
right waiting for his opportunity to
then come in and help to pronounce the
potential that's always been yes that
has always been implicit in a life and
the life and times about the violence
yeah it is Austin there's also there's a
couple of things like um so he's the
word so you know who is that Socrates
God Alka bodies it was a God who
prevented me from talking to you to say
so that so this so the sense of like a
god right the God prevented him from or
allowed him to make the wise choice of
timing essentially right of the right
moment I almost want to say I just
wanted to make a note of that right yes
yes that right cuz because but he's
because Socrates is Socrates's is is
deferring his own intuition to that of
that third factor we couldn't keep
talking about right like that and that
sort of that that that dialogic spirit
that is the transpersonal dialogic
spirit that then lets between the
dialogues and then descends to descends
to to guide and and provoke it that that
his that he continuously defers to that
as his his you know that's that that's
his that's his that's his tutor just as
yes tutor to all solutions it is also
it's interesting he also said here which
is this struck to me it's self
cultivation and he's talking about we
both need it right he said he's not he's
not like on one level he's being way
superior to him he's like knocking him
around right like slapping him around
you had to wake up basically but in
another level he's saying were both
dorks we both need to cultivate here
were bull riding the same boat which is
interesting
right well which helps to obviate the
risk of him becoming the object of love
an idolatrous worship right yeah because
it effectively he's saying it doesn't it
doesn't stop ID it doesn't stop here
yeah it doesn't stop it me this wisdom
just that I'm not the terminus of this
process yeah yeah I again I'm the
Midwife of the process right I'm the I'm
the bridge for the process I am
something through which the process
Travis I am NOT the terminus of that of
the process don't look at me look
through me but past yes look over my
shoulder look at what for me I want to
be looking yes I think he's prevented me
to talk about talking to you right now
yes yeah yeah yeah refer refer beyond me
refer beyond me right so he's pulling
he's pulling us ladies towards him but
he's also making sure that our bodies
isn't going to be falling into him
he still has some tension is still going
to be beyond so many things happening
right so I may be beyond you but there
is a great deal beyond me and so he
right he's served again he's maintaining
the tension yeah
he's positioning him between our bodies
and end the truth huh maintaining the
tension the attention is so
interestingly important throughout this
mm-hmm
like so so interesting how attention is
building and like on some level it's
almost like I would imagine the cue that
Socrates may be listening to or feeling
in what when he says what and how he
says it is very much has to do with
where the tension is right what were to
tighten it right where to open it right
like on some level he like I've been
sailor yeah absolutely
there you go yeah harnessing the wind so
let's say you want to keep you keep
reading oh yeah yeah let's do it
yeah I think you're teasing me Socrates
yes maybe but I'm I'm right in saying
that we stand in need of
self-cultivation actually every human
being needs self-cultivation but
especially the two of us you're right
about me and about me hmm
so there it is right there it is again
what so what should we do now there's
like then he brings him back with the
question now he's now were we
interesting what she right because
there's something about there's
something about Socrates humbling
himself that actually helps to that
actually helps to to relax Alcibiades a
little bit more into the process yeah
the Socrates if I can use this this very
this very this very generic theological
language but that Socrates is making
sure that he is imminent to Alcibiades
as well as being there in Cendant and so
the tension that we were just talking
about maintaining the totnes of that
tension yeah depends upon him being
properly equidistant yeah figuratively
between right Alcibiades and what what
is beyond us of IDs and so so but but
anytime that Socrates retreats too far
into the horizon the the project of
aspiration is discouraged yeah right so
Socrates has to make sure that he's
close enough to our societies versa for
Alcibiades to remain erratically
encouraged if I can use the metaphor of
eros they right right right yeah
somebody's has to be properly erotic
erotica kirti's has to be within range
of realness right within range of erotic
realness in order for Alcibiades to
continually be in order for his is his
interest to remain an adult and so
anytime Socrates begins to retreat to
far target ease brings himself back and
then if we notice right Alcibiades
relaxes again into the process and seems
all the more willing yeah okay
so what should we do there must be no
giving up my friend and no slacking off
nope Socrates that really wouldn't do
Noah wouldn't so let's work it out
together
tell me we say that we want to be as
good as possible don't we yes in what
respect
you're good my questions again you get
it you get a break from this big changes
[Laughter]
in what good men do obviously good at
what taking care of things obviously
what sorts of things horses of course
not in that case we'd consult a horse
expert yes well do you mean sailing no
in that case we'd consult the sailing
expert yes
well what sorts of things whose business
is it the leading citizens of Athens by
leading citizens do you mean clever men
or stupid men
clever but isn't everybody good at what
they're clever at yes and bad at what
they're not of course and is this she'd
make her clever at making shoes
certainly then he's good at it that's
right well now isn't the shoemaker
stupid at making clothes yes
so he's bad at that yes so the same
person is both good and bad at least by
this argument apparently do you mean to
say that good men are also bad of course
not
so which ones do you say are good men
I mean those with the ability to rule
the city but not I presume over horses
no of course not over people yes when
they're sick no when they're at sea no
when they're harvesting no when they're
doing nothing or when they're doing
something doing something doing what try
to make it clear for me it's when
they're helping each other and dealing
with each other as we do in our urban
way of life
so you mean ruling over men who deal
with men yes over the boats
Boatswain's who deal with road rowers of
course not that's the pilot I'm sorry
that's what the pilot is good at yes do
you mean ruling over flute players who
direct singers and deal with dancers of
course not again
what's what's the chorus master again
that's what the core course master is
good at certainly so what do you mean by
being able to rule over men who deal
with men
I mean ruling over the men in the city
who take part in citizenship and who
make a mutual contribution well what
skill is this suppose I asked you the
same thing again what skill makes men
understand how to rule over men who take
part in sailing the pilots and what
knowledge did we say enables them to
rule over those who take part in singing
the chorus masters as you just said well
now what do you call the knowledge that
enables you to rule over those who take
part in citizenship
I call it the knowledge of good advice
Socrates but then do you think the
pilots advice is bad advice of course
not
then is it good advice I should think so
yes to ensure the safety of his
passengers you're right
well then what's the purpose of this
good advice you're talking about the
safety and better management of the city
but what is present or absent when the
city is safe and better managed if for
example you asked me what is present or
absent in the body when it is safe and
better managed I'd reply health is
present and diseases absent when you
agree yes and if you think every time he
says and if you know he begins the
question with and if I'm like I've been
trained well so for the laughs and if
you asked me again what is present in
our eyes when they are bettered better
cared for I'd say the same sort of thing
sight is present and blindness is absent
again with our ears deafness is absent
and hearing is present when they're in
better condition and getting better
treatment they're right well then what
about a city what is it that presents or
present or absent when it is in a better
condition and getting better management
and treatment the way I look at at
socrates mutual friendship will be
present and hatred and insurrection will
be absent when you say
Frenship do you mean agreement or
disagreement agreement what skill is it
that makes cities agree about numbers
arithmetic what about private citizens
isn't it the same skill yes and doesn't
it also make each person agree with
himself yes and what skill is it that
makes each of us agree with himself and
about whether a hands width is larger
than an arm's length it's measuring
isn't it of course doesn't it make both
cities and private citizens agree yes
and isn't it the same with Wayne it is
well this agreement you're talking about
what is it what's it about what skill
provides it does the same skill make
both a city and a private citizen agree
both with themselves and with others
that does seem quite likely what is it
then don't give up try your best to tell
me ok so right there so it's like okay
something is doing so again I'm having
this sense of like he's presencing he's
he's presencing something by making it
profoundly like it's absence or just
being known it he has it build up and
linger there so it's this yeah it's like
I'm sitting here this slinking well what
is that thing like oh yeah there's a
hollow there's a hollow at the center of
the discussion yeah we're trying to
search some circle our way into the
hollow totally so it's like a Mesa I
don't mean circle in your ethical sense
or maybe I don't know you tell me I
think yeah like you don't know how
correct you are but tell me if you did
know you were for it how would you know
hahaha so this is so so that's important
too so
could just say he just could give a a
statement a proposition that would just
give the end conclusion but he's walking
around a hollow right and the more he
circles around it the more the presence
of what you don't know is starting to
become present this kind of sense of
lonely what you don't know is actually
pregnant
that's my presence that's right that's
right and then ironically or pitler I
should say not ironic I should say even
though there's irony involved but I
should say paradoxically as they enclose
as they enclosed it more and more and
more it deepens and deepens and deepens
right so the hollow appears to grow in
volume as they seem to get close as they
seem to encroach on it yeah
totally said that just so that seems to
okay so I saw if we're Socrates what is
it when Socrates understand or what is
it what is it that he's in a
relationship such that it occurs for him
not just to say it right like there's a
there's a right relationship to it such
that he's a tuning into something right
like it gets like the good or whatever
it is it's there's a virtue in this
right because it's right I think in some
sense the virtue in it is the intimacy
between he and Alcibiades because the
intim because it says though it's as
though socrates it's as though socrates
dwells somewhere at the circumference of
that hollow we keep talking about and as
Alcibiades advances into it he and
Socrates become more intimate which is
to say he becomes more intimate with the
with with with thee with thee was sort
of the the diaphanous nature of that
Hollow
right he closes in on it as he closes in
on it it opens more and more grave but
so too does his relationship with Socko
he's open more and more because Socrates
is I because that because that that
Hollow if I could keep referring to it
in that way oh it's something that he's
identifying through Socrates so as he
advances on it he's also advancing on
Socrates but both are becoming more
voluminous as he advances closer but if
we think about the virtue of that
advancement in terms of the into the
social intimacy of the two interlocutors
that make sense right because as they
come closer and closer Alcibiades
proximity to his ignorance in that
Hollow
you know begins to grow more and more
and more so what seems to guide the
conversation is the what what what like
that it's like the T of the the tellus
of the conversation is the relationship
between Socrates and Alcibiades but of
course the relationship between Socrates
and Alcibiades is also opening them to
so much more yeah so in some sense to me
what's guiding Socrates is precisely his
his intimacy with Alcibiades yeah so
it's interesting because so now he's
attuned into the the relationship right
that they're both having it is funny cuz
it's just not that long ago he he
started saying were both in the same
boat basically right right again because
he's maintaining yeah equidistance yeah
and then they then alkyl bodies had the
first weak question well how do we how
do we do it like we're both on the same
team now all of a sudden right and so
yeah so there's this way in which the
listening they're both walking together
a lot more right and that togetherness
is now has its own horizon that is now
starting to you can feel Socrates
starting to abide to it in guiding his
questions and because I do have this
sense of life of Socrates is actually
there's a vulnerability that's not it's
probably not easy to appreciate with
Socrates in this but there is a way in
which Socrates is vulnerable in all
I think so I think so yeah absolutely I
don't think this would work otherwise
because you can't you can't be hmm is
this true if even even as I find myself
wanting to say it you can't you like you
can't pet there can't be in at least in
the sense in which okay so I don't know
if this is true but I'm going to say it
anyway let's see it's as though there
can't be a proper seduction with an out
vulnerability on the part of the seducer
or at least not a sustainable long-term
renewable form of seduction with that
vulnerability on the part of the seducer
right but it occurs to me it might be
true
let's listen let's walk along with it a
little bit so it's like that seems like
it has to be true right otherwise
otherwise it's not a seduction it's like
more like a rape or it's like something
okay okay okay right like there's a
sense in which I think the vulnerability
isn't isn't one in which we're where
Alko bodies is clearly vulnerable right
like you know cuz he's he doesn't know
he's taken on this ride you know in
Socrates clearly has the deft hand and
he's been revealed to be destitute poor
and ugly and all the things that he
thought he wasn't because there's always
someone more handsome and more rich so
he's now in this position of extreme
vulnerable Socrates has got a care about
him mm-hmm
he couldn't be attuned and adjust
accordingly he could affect Socrates is
explicit he's like he thinks he's a dork
right he thinks he's just a foolish hey
so but there's in him he's only able to
say that right because he's revealing a
witnessing of him on such a level that
he's able to say that in a way that
doesn't just offend him but makes him I
think there's something about like the
first one to really care in all this is
Socrates like this is inside of
I think that's part of where Socrates is
vulnerable is like that he's got it like
for example the timing
right there is a sense in which if
you've done any acting or you've done
any teamwork or any kind of performance
or anything timing is the whole thing
right that's how it flows and there is
the sense where it's this this weird
place of like where
if you get the timing off the whole
thing just goes right see so you have to
actually you are in this place of just I
think that's the other other one sake
was kind of vulnerable is like he's
gotta be just constantly like this he
doesn't look like he's off balance in
fact it looks like I'll come by these is
off balance but Socrates is very much on
a Razors Edge with this and even says so
in the sense of like thank God the gods
are here like that I didn't step into
earlier just the right time there's this
element about timing too for Socrates is
vulnerable as well in different ways
right okay Jeb you keep going yeah let's
keep going and then and then I have to I
have to jump on another call at 4:00 so
just like couple minutes okay sounds
good okay where did we leave it
let's see here well I'll just go I'll
start up here
well disagreement you're talking about
what is that it hanger let's start from
the top of 584 so okay of course doesn't
it make both cities in private does it
make both cities and private citizens
agree yes and isn't it the same with
weighing it is well disagreement you're
talking about what is it what's it about
what skill provides it doesn't the same
skill make both a city and a private
citizen agree both with themselves and
with others that does seem quite likely
what is it then
don't give up don't you saying yeah
don't give up try your best to tell me
so right there he's really with them
yeah like I just feelings like you don't
give up he's like revealing how much
he's caring great yeah stay with me here
yeah yeah and it's because that's and
it's yes and the only reason that the
only reason that Alcibiades should
should should heed the direction is
because of the relationship that they
formed yeah yeah right if someone says
someone says you know trust me don't
give up if you have no relationship with
that person like that yeah
the encouragement means nothing yeah
right yeah unless it comes from
character unless it comes from yeah
unless it comes from from trustworthy
character so that's why the socialized
relationship between the two of them is
so integrally it's the binding it's the
it's the adhesive that keeps that keeps
him trained into the process yeah so
there's something also think like I
think what you said to it's like it
unless maybe there was character right
like that you could admire that you
could entrust so in some way we're also
kind of if we look at Socrates here is
some has something to do with the way
he's being in the dialogue is very very
much the function of what character
represents to us right right the
inviting of character right because then
the Socratic faith depants Eric
pratik faith is characterological right
Socratic faith depends upon upon upon
interpersonal yeah Socratic faith
depends upon supplant depends upon the
the interpersonal trust the relational
trust right right that is that is built
by and into character yes right the
character of faith that character word
is there's something about that that
kick character well we keep we keep
coming back to it right yeah we keep
coming back to it for a while yeah there
is something there that I mean that's in
some ways that is that the the most
punctuating answer to the question in
why dialogues why dialogues because
character yeah because character I think
that's the best it's like the Pythias
dancer I can come up with at least to
the glue and someone goes why are they
dialogues they're dialogue is because
character yes because without character
it doesn't matter right right right
character it's not relevant that
character it's not concern without
character it's not interest you know you
know it's interesting after it's not
ultimate anyway yeah I know exactly what
you mean when you say character but like
if you actually asked me what it is it
cut it kind of feels like that
it kind of feels like that know is right
it organs in the hollow it's in the
hollow there's something about it this
like I have just noticed that like you
keep coming back to character you and I
keep talking about it I even use it a
lot but I don't even know exactly why
they what it is exactly it's it's
mysterious mm-hmm but it's important
yeah we'll keep it we'll keep it mm-hmm
we'll keep it implicit for now at some
point maybe we'll we'll want to
interrogate it more yes yes
spoken like spoken like a true Socrates
haha let's keep it she's so lucky
yes all right my friend
okay we'll leave it here yes this is a
lot of fun sure was
yeah always this I come to look forward
to it yeah me too but okay
enjoy the rest the day right